PROFESSOR: Now we have all the ideas
we need to build the really killer
algorithm, the cornerstone of search
[? A ?] in AI, which is A star search.
A star search takes all these ideas
and puts them together.
Maybe some of you have heard the story
of the tortoise and the hare.
Have you heard the story of
the tortoise and the hare?
OK, so how's the story go?
You've got the tortoise, which
is slow and steady.
It's very careful.
It eventually gets to the goal,
but very, very deliberately.
You've got the hare, which zips straight
along, but then at some point
goes rogue and something goes wrong.
This should remind you of something
you've just seen.
Basically, this guy is Uniform Cost
Search, slow and steady, but
eventually gets there.
And then you've got the hare, which
is Greedy search, zips off in some
direction, maybe it's
the right direction.
What we want to do, the goal of this
entire endeavor is to build this.
We want to have something that's got
the properties of the turtle.
It's very slow.
It makes sure it hedges all of its bets,
but it's got some vision about
where it's going and it tries
to do things efficiently,
like the hare does.
So let's see how we can put
these two things together.
Now, it's kind of hard to bolt the
rabbit on top of the turtle, but it's
actually not so hard to bolt Uniform
Cost Search and Greedy together.
So let's see what they do and
how they do things wrong.
So here's a graph.
The start state is s.
The goal state is g.
The numbers h are the heuristics
at each point.
And the other numbers are
the action costs.
So Uniform Cost will explore ordering
based on the path cost, the cumulative
path cost, which is also sometimes
called the backward cost, g of n.
So for a node in the search tree, which
corresponds to a path in this
graph, it has some sum
of the action costs.
That's g of n for that node.
And Uniform Cost looks at all the cheap
paths first, which means at the
beginning, what's it going to do?
It's going to explore
out all this stuff.
Not because it's headed in
the right direction.
It's not.
The heuristic is telling
you to turn back.
Uniform Cost Search explores this stuff
towards c, not because it's
headed in the right direction,
but because it's cheap.
It does all the cheap stuff.
That's how it gets optimality.
What does Greedy do?
Well, Greedy is going to order by the
proximity of the goal, which means
after it expands the path s to a,
the next path it's going to for
is s to a to e.
Because even though it's really
expensive, look at that eight, it
looks like it gets it
close to the goal.
And Greedy has no clue about
expensive paths.
It only knows about closeness to goal.
So that number h, the heuristic,
is also sometimes
called the forward cost.
It's the cost of the remaining
part of getting to the goal.
So it's going to explore this red area
in order to find its first goal.
And so it does expensive things
that look good in the future.
Even though they're actually have
high cost and that can be
computed as you go.
So what does A star do?
It just adds these things together.
So in A star, you look at the
sum of the backward cost.
How much this plan actually
has cost you, plus the
forward cost, the heuristic.
How much you think it's going
to cost going forward.
Now these two numbers, it's important,
they're very different.
g sums up the action costs.
The heuristic is just for that one point
because the heuristic represents
the whole rest of the way to the goal.
So if you do A star, it won't go towards
c very early because the
heuristic is going to say
that's expensive.
The forward cost will be high.
And it's not going to spend time on this
branch that costs eight because g
will be very high.
It's going to basically
go down the center.
And that's a really nice property.
OK, because of g it knows to ignore
paths that are actually expensive.
And because of h it knows to ignore
paths that are going to be expensive.
All right, so, so far we've basically
got an algorithm.
We're going to order what take off the
fringe based on the sum of the
cumulative path cost of that node, all
the actions that led to it, plus the
heuristic, which comes out of
our heuristic function.
So let's execute it.
So here's a small graph.
It shouldn't be too bad.
We start with our fringe having just
the empty plan starting at s.
And what's it's priority?
So we can have g here and h here.
It's its backward cost, which
is zero-- right, we
haven't done anything--
plus its forward cost, which is from
the heuristic, which is three.
So it's total cost is three.
We pop that.
On go it's children.
s to a, that's one successor.
s to b.
What are their Priorities s to a has
backward cost two, and forward cost
two, for total cost of four.
s to b has a backward cost of two
and forward cost of one, for a
total cost of three.
What comes off first?
S to b.
What's its child?
s to b to g, which has a backward cost
of five, forward cost of zero, total
cost of five.
OK, if I said I found the goal.
I just found the successor that's a goal
and I returned it, I would return
the path s to b to g.
And that would be bad because it costs
five and s to a to g only costs four.
So even though I found this lower
path, why did I find it first?
I found it first because the heuristic
made it appealing to
check into it first.
The reason why we leave things on the
fringe until we dequeue them is
because s to a still holds out hope
of being better than this path.
And in fact, it will be.
So I do not yet declare victory.
I pop off s to a.
I get s to a to g, which has backward
cost four, forward cost
zero, total cost four.
Then, this is now the cheapest
thing on the fringe.
I pop it off.
I see it passed the goal test.
And I return it.
So this is critical.
You stop when you dequeue the
goal from the fringe, not
when you enqueue it.
Otherwise, you will make mistakes.
So that's lesson number one.
That goal test really matters
when you execute it.